<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Blog - natfan.github.io</title><link>https://natfan.github.io/blog/index.html</link>
<description>Natfan's Personal Blog</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 23:31:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 23:31:07 +0100</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://natfan.github.io/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Elaborate Hacking Montage
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>So, going off my previous post about <a href="https://natfan.github.io/blog/hacking-or-tangent.html">Hacking on WikiHow</a>, I got into a bit of a tangent and it became rather wholesome. Today, I've decided that I'm going to finish off that original train of thought.

<p><a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Become-a-Hacker">Honestly, I agree with a lot of what the article said.</a> You really should learn how operating systems function, what the actual code behind the language does, the advantages and disadvantages of each language and operating systems. Most of the advice in the article is good. My main issue isn't really of the content, although I think that some stuff can be added, which I will explain later. My issue is the order in which  the article is presented.

<p>HyperText Markup Language, or HTML, should <b>never</b> be your first language. HTML is <i>not</i> a programming language, and should not be treated as such. Learning HTML is very important, as website design is an important skill, but it shouldn't be considered a programming language as this can lead to bad habits down the road. I would recommend <a href="https://python.org/"<b>python</b></a>, if you're older than about 15, or <a href="https://scratch.mit.edu/"<b>Scratch</b></a> if not. Both are very easy to learn and teach the core concepts of programming such as:

<ul>
    <li>variables,
    <li>functions,
    <li>objects,
    <li>syntax,
    <li>data structures,
    <li>programmatic logic,
    <li>debugging
</ul>

<p>Another thing that I disagreed with in the article was that it said that you should "learn a martial art". I honestly feel that this is just someone with an agenda who really wants other people to take up the arts. I do not consider "learning a martial art" as a must-have for every hacker on the planet. It just sounds pretentious and stupid, in my opinion.

<p>I'd also argue that "fighting authority" isn't a hacker-y thing to do. While it may seem that way in the movies, with l33t t33n h4xorz breaking into evil banks and shady corporations, real hacking should be about working together with others to find a solution to an issue. If all hackers "hated authority", then who would work for Internet censorship software companies or work on ethical penetration testing for large corporations who have probably broken a few laws in their time.

<p>I'd argue that "being competent" is not really a valuable skill as a hacker. Before you close this tab in dismay, hear me out. I feel that the only thing that a hacker <i>really</i> needs in his or her toolkit is the ability to ask questions well. I would recommend reading through <a href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/smart-questions.html">Eric Steven Raymond's piece on Asking Questions The Smart Way</a>. While it may look like a very old paper, it was last updated in 2014 to incorporate StackOverflow, so I think it's worth the read. Every hacker had to start somewhere, and we were probably all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Script_kiddie">script kiddies</a> at one point. The way we got out of this rut is by knowing how things worked so we could develop programs of our own. And how did we achieve this, you may ask? By <b>asking questions</b>. Yes, everyone needs to ask questions, because as I said in my previous post, <b>no one knows everything</b>.

<p>I agree with the open-source aspect of things, but I'd say that you do not need to release every program you make as open source. If you write code well and you create a product that people want, you could just give it away for free then open it up to allow others to contribute later if they want to. I'd recommend keeping a few cards close to your chest at any one time, especially if you're new to the scene. There's nothing worse than having your ideas stolen by someone with more influence than you, so maybe keep the inner workings of some of your higher level programs to yourself for now.

<p>Going back to my previous point, if you feel that you are capable of helping others every now and again, do it! You know how you felt at the start of your journey, so browse StackOverflow or some other development forum, and help out newbies. Try to be kind and not condescending in your answers, but <b>do NOT spoon-feed them code</b>. This practice will never help then learn.

<p>That's about it for this post. If you think I did wrong somewhere, let me know! I'd love to have a discussion with you, so tweet me your thoughts.

<p>In more meta news, I'm going to try to work on getting Disqus set up so that I can have a proper comments section rather than people just  tweeting me.

<p>Yours,
<p>Natfan.

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_post.html'>post</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="https://natfan.github.io/blog/elaborate-hacking-montage.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
<a href="https://twitter.com/share" class="twitter-share-button" data-text="&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;" data-url="https://natfan.github.io/blog/elaborate-hacking-montage.html"
 data-via="NathanWindisch"
>Tweet</a>	<script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js";fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,"script","twitter-wjs");</script>
</p>
]]></description><link>https://natfan.github.io/blog/elaborate-hacking-montage.html</link>
<guid>https://natfan.github.io/blog/./elaborate-hacking-montage.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Nathan Windisch</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 12:58:46 +0100</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Hacking or Tangent
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>So I as I was lying in bed last night I decided to browse some <a href="https://wikihow.com/">WikiHow</a> on my phone for LULZ. I started looking at their "Computers and Electronics" section, to see if I could learn anything new. After all, I pride myself in <i>not knowing everything</i>. If I did know everything there was to know about everything, I'd be simultaneously very rich and very bored. What's the point of living if you can't learn a few new tricks every now and again? For example, I literally just got distracted for about 5 minutes trying to unbind my Backspace key. Why? Because I remembered that I had set my right Alt key to be Backspace too, so now I have decided that I may as well try to force myself to use it permanently.

<p>You may be asking yourself:

<p><q>But why Nathan?! Why would you force yourself to do something that really doesn't need to be done?</q>

<p>Well, my friend, the answer to that is simple. Why do anything, ever? Honestly, it's a good question, and one that I can answer with two simple points:

<ol>
    <li>If it has to be done or,
    <li>If it's fun.
</ol>

<p>There's really no other reason for doing anything, if you boil it down. Why did the Europeans try to find the New World? A little column A, a little column B. They felt that plundering the new seas was necessary to their respective empires, and because they thought it'd be a laugh. <sup><sup><sup><sup>Probably, I'm not a historian.

<p>The main point of all of this is that there is a reason for all of this. There is a reason for almost everything I do, be it simply getting out of bed in the morning, going to school (soon to be work), hacking code together, playing video games, writing this very blog, even staring into space. Everything that everyone does can be split into one of the two categories, and it is important that we get a mix of the two together to get a strong and stable work/life balance. If we do too many things just because they have to be done, then we'll spend all our time never focusing on the little things in life like the dust in sunbeams, that cute girl that smiled at you in the restaurant or the support network that your friends and family give you, I hope. On the flip side of the coin, if we spend too much time doing things just because they are fun, we can cease to be a productive and functional member of society.

<p>If you are one of the rare few people that gets to do things that they have to that are also fun, treasure it. Most people hate their jobs, so I'm told. You're one of the lucky few that broke that cycle and did a blend of the two. What you get to do is incredible, make the most of it. You never know how much time you have left, so live every minute to the fullest.

<p>If you're with the rest of us, try not to get too down in the dumps. 99% of the world has to do stuff that they'd really rather not do so that they can keep eating, drinking and having their standard of living stay at the same rate. And that's fine, it really is. Like I said before, it's only a few of us get to do what we <i>really</i> want to do. It's what we do with our free time that matters. Go out, meet up with your mates, dance with the opposite sex, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Playtest_(Black_Mirror)">call your mum</a> or do anything else that you think might just be fun, interesting, social or down right weird. No one knows where the next step will take you, but you can have a lot of fun while you're getting there.

<p>Damn, that was a bit of a tangent, wasn't it? All because I decided to change up my UX a little. I guess I'll talk about WikiHow's "l33t h4x" another time, but for now I think I'm gonna sign off for the night.

<p>Good night all, I wish you all the very best in literally anything (productive or fun) that you do.

<p>Yours,
<p>Natfan.

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_post.html'>post</a></p>




<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="https://natfan.github.io/blog/hacking-or-tangent.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
<a href="https://twitter.com/share" class="twitter-share-button" data-text="&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;" data-url="https://natfan.github.io/blog/hacking-or-tangent.html"
 data-via="NathanWindisch"
>Tweet</a>	<script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js";fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,"script","twitter-wjs");</script>
</p>
]]></description><link>https://natfan.github.io/blog/hacking-or-tangent.html</link>
<guid>https://natfan.github.io/blog/./hacking-or-tangent.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Nathan Windisch</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:19:13 +0100</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
